

ramya.rengasamy27@gmail.com



+91 9003131706



Chennai, India

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.E-Instrumentation Control Engineering** 

A.V.C College Of Engineering : 2013 - 2017

Mayiladuthurai, Tamilnadu

#### **TECHNOLGIES**

Java (OOPS, Collections and other libs)

Selenium WebDriver

FIGMA

POM

**TestNG** 

Data Driven Framework

**BDD Cucumber** 

Junit

PostMan

**GitHUB** 

**Functional Testing** 

Test case Development

Maven

## CERTIFICATIONS

Completed ISTQB Foundation level certification with ISTB board - April 2024

Completed Versant Test (English proficiency ) with B2 grade - April 2024

# Ramya Rengasamy

### SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

#### **PROFILE**

Over 4+ years of experience in the testing field, including test development and management for multiple clients, including Insurance agencies and enterprise clients nationwide. Experience includes reviewing and testing functionality of software applications and programs, as well as evaluating system compatibility and functionality across multiple platforms.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Performance Analyst (Quality Engineer)

Feb 2020 to Present

Full Creative , Chennai

**OPS Desk Technician**Full Creative, Chennai

June 2017 to Feb 2020

- QA with around 4+ years in both Automation and Manual testing of Web applications.
- Extensive experience in E-Commerce and insurance domain.
- Experience working in a highly Agile distributed team with Scrum processes. Working knowledge of Software development (SDLC) and Software Testing (STLC) processes.
- Analyzing Business Requirements / Features and preparing the Test conditions
- Experience testing web based application with Selenium (WebDriver) with Java Good knowledge of Core Java and OOPS – Object Oriented Programming Structure.
- Having good experience in different automation frameworks like Cucumber (BDD), Junit, TestNG, POM and Data driven framework.
- Experience in build automation tools like Maven and Version Control is done with GIT.
- Good experience in writing X-path to identify web elements.
- Experience with Test Driven Development (TDD) and Behaviour Driven Development (BDD).
- Ability debugging the test cases and fixing errors and defect reporting and tracking the defects through JIRA.
- Involved in Agile Ceremonies like Daily Scrum call, Sprint Planning, Sprint Review and Retrospective.
- Having good knowledge and understanding with API Testing with (Postman)

#### **Project Details**

#### The AA (Report A Breakdown)

Automation and Manual Tester | April 2022 to March 2023

#### Tools & Technologies:

Core Java, Selenium WebDriver, Bdd Cucumber, PostMan, JIRA (Kanban and scrum), GIT, Jenkins

#### Responsibilities:

Participated in All agile ceremonies.

Analyzing and Understanding user stories and acceptance criteria.

Identifying the test scenarios that need to be automated.

Prepared and executed Test Cases as per System Requirements and User Stories. Prepared Features and automation scripts in Selenium with Cucumber.

Implemented different Automation frameworks like JUNIT, BDD (cucumber), POM, Data Driven, Maven using Selenium WebDriver and Core Java.

Prepared Reusable methods to improve productivity and maintainability.

Prepared POJO Classes to maintain the locators for every WebPages.

Executed and debug test scripts.

Good Experience in Resolving Conflicts while using GIT.

Performed Defect tracking and management in JIRA.

Track Bug Report to its closure, Logging Defects in Defect tracking tool for failed scenario and retesting it on upcoming build. Perform Cross browser testing to check the compatibility and stability of the application.

Extensively automated Regression testing and generating Reports through Jenkins. Involved in all levels of Agile starting from Test Planning to Retrospective meeting.

#### Canadian Tire (Ecommerce Application )

Manual and Automation Test Engineer | March, 2020 - Feb 2021

#### Tools & Technologies:

Core Java, Selenium WebDriver, TestNG, Data driven Framework, POM, JIRA, GIT,

#### Responsibilities:

Analyze test cases and identify the test cases that can be automated and manually tested. Preparing the functional test cases in excel.

Execute the cases on the new build

Reassign the defect if the retest got failed.

Analyze the changes in the new build and update the test cases accordingly. Capture all the results in a new folder for future tracking.

Perform retest and close the defect after defect deployment

Upload test evidences in JIRA under corresponding user stories.

Keeping track of Hardware and software requirements for the Test Environment Prepared the POM classes for the easy accessibility.

Good Experience in Resolving conflicts and Involved in Push, Pull, Merge the source code from GIT.

Detecting the defects and classifying those based on the priority and severity. Good in Java language programming and finding X-path locators.

Implemented different automation frameworks like Pom, TestNG.

Involved in Bug fixing for the defects raised during UAT.

Interact with Development team for the bug fixing and requirement clarity.